<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    Название
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">AstroAxis</string>
    <string name="description_name" translatable="false">astronomical reference book</string>

    Главное меню входа
    <string name="main_menu">Main menu</string>
    <string name="planets">Planets</string>
    <string name="planet">Planet</string>
    <string name="help">Help</string>
    <string name="exit">Exit</string>
    <string name="model">Model</string>
    <string name="back">➥</string>
    <string name="theory">Theory</string>
    <string name="loading">Loading</string>
    <string name="loading_model">Loading the model</string>
    <string name="error_loading_model">Error loading the model</string>
    <string name="exit_application">Exiting the application</string>
    <string name="confirmation_exit_application">Do you really want to exit the app ?!</string>

    Справка
    <string name="help_text">
        Astral Axis is an android reference application to help high school students learn astronomy.
        The Planets section contains basic information about the planets of the Solar System,
        where you can read brief information about them, as well as consider their 3D models.
        The Theory section contains basic theoretical information on the astronomy course in high school.
        There is also a table with the translation of astronomical units of measurement.
        Please leave a review on the app in RuStore or on the GitHub site in Releases.
    </string>

    <string name="link_GitHub" translatable="false">
        https://github.com/LebedevSergeyVach/AstroAxis
    </string>

    <string name="link_RuStore" translatable="false">
        https://www.rustore.ru/catalog/app/com.astro.axis.planet.libgdx
    </string>

    Планеты
    <string name="Sun">Sun</string>
    <string name="Mercury">Mercury</string>
    <string name="Venus">Venus</string>
    <string name="Earth">Earth</string>
    <string name="Mars">Mars</string>
    <string name="Jupiter">Jupiter</string>
    <string name="Saturn">Saturn</string>
    <string name="Uranium">Uranium</string>
    <string name="Neptune">Neptune</string>
    <string name="Pluto">Pluto</string>
    <string name="planetName" translatable="false">planetName</string>

    Таблица
    <string name="name">Name</string>
    <string name="radius">Radius</string>
    <string name="mass">Weight</string>
    <string name="density">Density</string>
    <string name="average_temperature">Average temperature</string>
    <string name="number_of_satellites">Number of satellites</string>
    <string name="main_satellites">Main satellites</string>
    <string name="the_speed_of_rotation_around_its_axis">The speed of rotation around its axis</string>
    <string name="the_speed_of_rotation_around_the_Sun">The speed of rotation around the Sun</string>
    <string name="rotation_period">Rotation period</string>
    <string name="the_orbital_period">The orbital period</string>
    <string name="large_semi_axis">Large semi-axis</string>
    <string name="rings">The presence of rings</string>
    <string name="quantity_ring">Number of rings</string>
    <string name="giant">Number of rings</string>
    <string name="the_presence_of_an_atmosphere">The presence of an atmosphere</string>
    <string name="atmospheric_layers">Layers of the atmosphere</string>
    <string name="internal_structure">Internal structure</string>
    <string name="features">Features</string>

    Теория
    <string name="theory_of_astronomy">Theoretical reference book</string>
    <string name="guide">Guide</string>

    <string name="schematic_representation_of_the_celestial_sphere">
        Schematic representation of the celestial sphere
    </string>
    <string name="horizontal_coordinate_system">Horizontal coordinate system</string>

    <string name="link_guide_pdf" translatable="false">
        https://docs.yandex.ru/docs/view?tm=1712343804&amp;tld=ru&amp;lang=ru&amp;name=65777082.pdf&amp;text=Основные%20иены%20измерения%20астрономия%2011%20класс&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.litres.ru%2Fget_pdf_trial%2F65777082.pdf&amp;lr=65&amp;mime=pdf&amp;l10n=ru&amp;sign=5f049789bcb124afa918d794e59be610&amp;keyno=0&amp;serpParams=tm%3D1712343804%26tld%3Dru%26lang%3Dru%26name%3D65777082.pdf%26text%3D%25D0%259E%25D1%2581%25D0%25BD%25D0%25BE%25D0%25B2%25D0%25BD%25D1%258B%25D0%25B5%2B%25D0%25B8%25D0%25B5%25D0%25BD%25D1%258B%2B%25D0%25B8%25D0%25B7%25D0%25BC%25D0%25B5%25D1%2580%25D0%25B5%25D0%25BD%25D0%25B8%25D1%258F%2B%25D0%25B0%25D1%2581%25D1%2582%25D1%2580%25D0%25BE%25D0%25BD%25D0%25BE%25D0%25BC%25D0%25B8%25D1%258F%2B11%2B%25D0%25BA%25D0%25BB%25D0%25B0%25D1%2581%25D1%2581%26url%3Dhttps%253A%2F%2Fwww.litres.ru%2Fget_pdf_trial%2F65777082.pdf%26lr%3D65%26mime%3Dpdf%26l10n%3Dru%26sign%3D5f049789bcb124afa918d794e59be610%26keyno%3D0
    </string>

    <string name="description_schematic_representation_of_the_celestial_sphere">" One of the most important astronomical
        tasks, without which it is impossible to solve all other problems of astronomy, is determining the position of a
        celestial body on the celestial sphere. \n\n In ancient times, people believed that all stars were located on
        the celestial sphere, which as a whole rotates around the Earth. This impression is due to the fact that, as a
        result of the immense distance of celestial bodies, the human eye is unable to assess the differences in
        distances to them, and they appear equally distant. With the development of scientific knowledge, such a view of
        the celestial sphere faded away. However, the geometry of the celestial sphere laid down in ancient times,
        through development and refinement, has taken on its modern form, which is used in astrometry. \n\n The
        celestial sphere is an imaginary sphere of arbitrary radius, onto which objects visible in the sky are
        projected, with the observer assumed to be at its center (Fig. 1). \n\n Distances on the celestial sphere can
        only be measured in angular units: degrees, minutes, seconds, or radians. For example, the angular diameters of
        the Moon and the Sun are approximately 30 minutes. \n\n One of the main directions relative to which the
        position of a celestial body is determined is the vertical line. The vertical line, passing through the center
        of the celestial sphere, intersects it at the zenith Z and the nadir Z′. The zenith is directly above the
        observer. \n\n The plane passing through the center of the celestial sphere and perpendicular to the vertical
        line intersects the celestial sphere along a great circle – the line of the mathematical (true) horizon. \n\n
        The celestial pole is the point on the celestial sphere around which the apparent daily motion of the stars
        occurs due to the Earth's rotation around its axis. \n\n The celestial axis (PP′) is the line around which the
        apparent rotation of the celestial sphere occurs. It intersects the celestial sphere at the north celestial pole
        P and the south celestial pole P′. The daily motion of celestial bodies appears as if the entire celestial
        sphere rotates as a whole around the celestial axis from east to west. This motion is apparent: it reflects the
        true motion – the Earth's rotation around its axis from west to east. \n\n The celestial equator is a great
        circle of the celestial sphere, the plane of which passes through the center of the celestial sphere and is
        perpendicular to the celestial axis. The celestial equator intersects the horizon at the points of east E and
        west W. The celestial meridian is a great circle of the celestial sphere passing through the zenith and the
        celestial poles. The celestial meridian intersects the horizon at the points of north N and south S. \n\n The
        angle between the celestial axis and the mathematical horizon is equal to the geographic latitude (φ) of the
        observation site. The great circle of the celestial sphere along which the apparent annual motion of the Sun
        occurs is called the ecliptic. The ecliptic intersects the equator at specific points: the vernal equinox (^)
        and the autumnal equinox (d)."
    </string>

    <string name="description_horizontal_coordinate_system">" Systems of celestial coordinates are used in astronomy to
        describe the position of celestial bodies in the sky or points on an imaginary celestial sphere. Several systems
        of celestial coordinates are used in astronomy, convenient for solving various scientific and practical
        problems. The known planes, circles, and points of the celestial sphere are used. \n\n The systems of celestial
        coordinates differ from each other in the choice of the main plane and the origin of the coordinate system.
        Depending on the task at hand, it may be more convenient to use one system or another. The most commonly used
        are the horizontal and equatorial coordinate systems. \n\n To construct a system of celestial coordinates, one
        should select a certain main plane passing through the observer and intersecting the celestial sphere along a
        great circle. Then, through the pole of this circle and the celestial body, another great circle is drawn,
        intersecting the first one, and as coordinates, the angular distance from the point of intersection to the
        celestial body and the angular distance from a certain point on the main circle to the same point of
        intersection are taken. In the horizontal coordinate system, the main plane is the plane of the horizon, and in
        the equatorial coordinate system, it is the plane of the celestial equator. \n\n The horizontal coordinate
        system is a system of celestial coordinates in which the center is placed at the observer's location on the
        Earth's surface, and the main plane is the plane of the mathematical horizon. One of the coordinates is either
        the altitude of the celestial body h or its zenith distance z. The other coordinate is the azimuth A (Fig.
        2). \n\n Altitude (h) is one of the coordinates of a celestial body in the horizontal coordinate system; it is
        measured along the circle passing through the zenith and the celestial body and expressed as the length of the
        arc of this circle from the horizon to the celestial body. This coordinate is analogous to geographic latitude.
        Altitudes are measured in the range from 0 to +90° towards the zenith and from 0 to +90° towards the nadir."
    </string>

</resources>
